（テンテン）いくわよ　リー。
Here I come, Lee!
（リー）いつでも。
I'm ready!
ハァ～ッ！
フッ！
表蓮華。
Primary Lotus!
どうよ？　限界以上の重さでしょ。
How's that?
It's heavier than what
you can handle, right?
うわぁ～っ！
リー。
Lee!
リー？
Lee?
さっさと出てきなさいよ　リー。
これくらいなによ！
Come up, Lee!
That was nothing!
リー！
Lee!
《昔の私が夢見ていたこと》
I used to dream about this
when I was a little girl.
綱手様っていうんだよ。
え？
Her name is Lady Tsunade.
すごい強いんだって。
そう　伝説のくノ一　綱手様。
They say she's really strong!
Yes! That's Lady Tsunade,
the legendary kunoichi!
決めた。　私　綱手様になる。
I've decided!
I'm going to become Lady Tsunade!
（ガイ）ついに今日からお前たちも
下忍になった。
From today, you are all genin.
そこでお前たちの目指すものを
聞いてみたい。
I want to take this time
to hear your goals.
（ネジ）答えたくない。
（ガイ）フム。
I don't want to answer that.
先生　たとえ忍術や幻術は
使えなくても→
Sensei!
I want to prove that even without
mastering ninjutsu or genjutsu,
立派な忍者になれることを
証明したいんです。
one can become a great ninja!
それが　僕のすべてです。
That is what I live for!
フッ。
君　何がおかしい！
Hey! What's so funny?!
お前　忍術も幻術も使えないって
時点で忍者じゃないだろ。
Listen, if you can't use ninjutsu
or genjutsu, you can't be a ninja.
なんだ？　バカか？
What? Are you stupid?
いや　熱血さえあれば
そうともかぎらないぞ。
No. That's not necessarily true,
if one has the passion.
ハハッ　よきライバルと青春し
競い合い高め合えば→
If you spend your youth
with a good rival,
sparring together
and honing your skills,
きっと立派な忍者になれる。
努力は必要だけどな。
there's no doubt
you will become a fine ninja.
But you will need determination.
はい。
うん。　で　君は？
Yes!
And you?
あっ　私は伝説のくノ一
綱手様になりたいです。
Oh, I want to become
the legendary kunoichi, Lady Tsunade!
あっ　エヘッ。
Ah, My Hero Lady Tsunade
Youth! Fight!
青春　ファイト。
（３人）ファイト。
– Fight!
綱手様か。
とにかく体術がすごかった。
LadyTsunade, huh.
Her taijutsu was simply amazing.
She has monster-like strength.
怪力の持ち主でな。
伝説の三忍の仲間→
There are rumors that she almost killed
her teammate Master Jiraiya,
自来也様を半殺しにしたという
噂もある。
who along with her was
one of the Legendary Sannin.
What must I do to become that strong?
どうしたら
そんなに強くなれるんですか？
Sheer determination!
努力あるのみ。
– Fight!
ファイト。
ファイト！
Fight!
1121! 1122!
１，１２１　１，１２２　１，１２３　１，１２４。
– 1123! 1124!
– Eleven hundred and…
– 1125, 1126!
１，１２５　１，１２６。
千百…。
1154, 1155!
１，１５４　１，１５５。
1156, 1157, 1158, 1159.
１，１５６　１，１５７。
ググ…。
１，１５８　１，１５９…。
1160!
やぁ～！
ぴゃ！？
Okay, Lee! Go!
（ガイ）よし　いけ！　リー！
はっ！　やぁ～！
（テンテン）ハァ…。
ん？
I'm trying my best,
努力はしてるんだけどなぁ
全然　強くならない。
but I'm not getting any stronger.
綱手様にたどり着くのに
どれだけ　かかるんだろう。
How long will it take to get
to Lady Tsunade's level?
ふむ…。
Lady Tsunade inherited
the talents of the First Hokage.
綱手様は　初代火影の
才能を受け継ぐお方だからな。
So are you saying talent is
more important than determination?
それって　努力より才能って
言ってませんか？
Oh no!
What I'm trying to say is
あ…　いやいやいや。
俺が言いたいのは→
that each shinobi is suited
to different things.
忍にも　それぞれ
向き不向きがあるということだ。
テンテンに怪力が身につくかどうかは
誰にもわからん。
No one can say whether
you will develop superhuman
strength or not, Tenten.
うわぁ～！
それまで。
Stop right there!
Lady Tsunade has more than
just monster strength, right?
綱手様
怪力だけじゃないんですよね？
Right. She is a specialist
in Medical Ninjutsu.
おう　医療忍術のスペシャリストだ。
どんな病気もケガも→
They say that there isn't an illness
or injury that Lady Tsunade can't heal.
綱手様に治せぬものは
ないという話だぞ。
Please teach me Medical Ninjutsu!
私にも医療忍術を教えてください。
まあ　俺の場合
医療忍術というか何というか→
Well, what I teach is a little different
from Medical Ninjutsu.
ちょっと違うんだな。
How do you do it?
どんなやり方ですか？
僕にも教えてください！
Please teach me too!
（ガイ）え？　おぉ。
う～ん　まあその…。
Yes, well…
なんだ　気合いと根性だ。
It's energy and guts!
Oh, that again.
な～んだ…。
だが　医療忍術を覚えたいという→
Still, I think you have passion
in wanting to learn Medical Ninjutsu!
テンテンの熱血は　すばらしいぞ。
これこそ青春！
That's the right spirit!
I will speak to
the Medical Corps for you.
医療班に
俺が話をつけておいてやろう。
やった～！
Yes!
上級医療技術の講義は　これまで。
That ends the lecture
on high-level Medical Ninjutsu.
We will now begin hands-on training.
では　実技に移りましょう。
はい！
All right.
医療忍術は　その名のとおり→
As its name suggests,
Medical Ninjutsu is ninjutsu used
in healing by controlling chakra.
チャクラをコントロールして
治療に使う忍術です。
はい。
Yes!
You use your own chakra to stimulate
the chakra network of your patient…
自分のチャクラで
相手のチャクラの経絡を刺激し…。
はい。
Yes.
細胞を活性化させ…。
and revitalize the cells.
はぁ～！
あ…。
君　たぶん…。
I think perhaps…
（テンテン）向いてないって言われた～。
I was told I wasn't suited for it!
（ガイ）ハハハハ！　まあ気にするな。
Well, don't let it bother you.
医療忍術が使えなくても
立派なくノ一は　いくらでもいる。
There are many fine kunoichi
who cannot perform Medical Ninjutsu.
But I want to become like
the legendary Lady Tsunade.
では私は　伝説の綱手様のように
なりたいんです！
Isn't there any other skill that
makes Lady Tsunade legendary?
他に何かないんですか？
綱手様の伝説。
う～む…　口寄せの術だな。
There is the Summoning Jutsu.
巨大なナメクジを口寄せする。
She can summon a giant slug.
That's why she was also
called the Slug Princess.
だから　ナメクジ姫などと
呼ばれたこともある。
The Summoning Jutsu?
口寄せの術？
あぁ　そうだ。
Yes, that's right.
口寄せの術って
どうすればできるんですか？
How do you do Summoning Jutsu?
あぁ　あれは
時空間忍術の一種だからな。
Well, it's a type of
Transportation Technique.
まず　その才能があるかどうかだ。
But first we have to see if
you have the skill to use it.
よし　いいな。　やってみろ。
All right, ready?
Try it.
はっ！
でた！
すごい！
Something appeared!
Amazing!
時空間忍術の才能は
あるようだな。
It seems you have the ability to do
the Transportation Technique.
うむ…　となれば→
Now, you need to enter into
a contract with the one you will summon.
口寄せする相手と
契約を結べばいい。
口寄せの術！
Summoning Jutsu!
ん～？
ガイ　これが　お前の生徒たちか？
Guy, are these your students?
It spoke!
しゃべった！
忍亀か。
A ninja tortoise?
さすが　ガイ先生です！
あの…　ナメクジは　いませんか？
Way to go, Guy Sensei!
– Umm…
– Huh?
You don't have a slug?
（ガイ）ナメクジより
カメのほうがいいだろう。
Isn't a tortoise better than a slug?
何じゃと　小娘！
わしの何が不満じゃ！？
What did you say, little girl?
Do you have something against me?
え～と…
伝説になってないとこかな。
Well, you're just not legendary,
I guess.
無礼者め！　契約など
こちらから願い下げじゃ！
Such insolence!
Well, I refuse to enter into
a contract with you!
い～だ！
Tenten, don't be so selfish!
テンテン　わがまま言うな。
It's not easy to find a partner
for a summoning contract!
口寄せの契約を
結んでくれる相手は→
そう簡単に見つかるもんじゃない。
え？　そうなの？
Oh? Is that so?
まぁ　それでも
練習は続けておくことだ。
Anyway, keep training!
Okay.
はい…。
他に綱手様の伝説はありますか？
Is there anything else
that Lady Tsunade is legendary for?
ん？
あとは伝説になるほど
酒と博打が趣味とか。
Well, her love of sake and
gambling is legendary.
However, you can't emulate that.
だが　それを真似てみてもなぁ。
KURAKU
SAKE
However, you can't emulate that.
お前　女の子だろう。
ハハッ　無理だ　無理だ。　ハハハハ！
I mean, you're just a little girl.
It's impossible.
（テンテン）酒！
Sake!
The drinking age is twenty.
お酒は二十歳になってから。
ニャン。
ちょっと　離しなさいよ！　バカ！
GAMBLING HOUSE
MARUSEI
Hey! Let me go! Stupid!
ニャン！　ニャン！
I'm going to become just like
the legendary kunoichi, Lady Tsunade!
私は伝説の　くノ一
綱手様みたいになるんだから！
綱手様だと！？　だったら　もっと
大きくなってから来るんだな！
Did you say Lady Tsunade?
Then come back when
you're much bigger!
綱手様はな
伝説の巨乳の持ち主なんだぞ！
Lady Tsunade's big chest
is legendary!
伝説の…　巨乳…。
Legendary…big chest.
今日こそ
今日こそ勝ってみせますよ　ネジ！
Today is the day!
I'm going to beat you, Neji!
だぁ～！
ん？　どうした？　青春の悩みか？
What's the matter?
Something troubling your youthful heart?
あぁっ！
リー！　ほんと　あんたってば
懲りないんだから。
Lee, you never learn, do you?
勝てっこないでしょ！
ネジは　あんたと違って…。
You can't beat him!
Neji's not like you.
天才なんだから。
He's a genius.
Lee! Come up!
リー！　出てきてよ！
あんた
絶対あきらめないんでしょ！
You never give up, right?
Lee?!
リー！
Stop, Lee!
やめろ　リー！
こいつ　敵に操られているぞ！
He's being controlled
by the enemy!
Neji, find the user of the jutsu.
I'll stop Lee!
ネジは術者を捜せ！
リーは　俺が止める！
ギャパパパ～！
If you cannot use
ninjutsu or genjutsu,
（ネジ）忍術や幻術が使えなければ→
you'll definitely be susceptible
to an enemy's jutsu.
敵の術にかかりやすいのは当然だ。
（ガイ）うん。
そんなやつと
チームを組むのは不安だ。
It makes me uneasy to be on
the same team with someone like that.
うん…。
うぉ～！　おっ！？
いくら努力したって　僕は→
No matter how hard I try,
I keep thinking,
強くなれないんじゃないかって…。
"What if I don't get any stronger?"
It scares me so much
that I can't take it!
怖くて怖くて　たまらないんです！
自分を信じないやつなんかに
努力する価値はない。
If you don't have faith in yourself,
it's not worth the effort!
たとえ
忍術や幻術は使えなくても→
"Even if I can't do ninjutsu
or genjutsu,"
"I want to prove that
I can become a fine shinobi."
立派な忍者になれることを
証明したいんです…　ってな。
Isn't that your Ninja Way?
それが　お前の忍道だろ。
いい目標じゃないか。
I think that's a wonderful goal!
（ガイ）体術だけのお前が
忍術や幻術に対抗するなら→
If you intend to take on ninjutsu
and genjutsu with only your taijutsu,
you must perfect your taijutsu
so that it can be superior to them.
それを上回る体術を
身につけねばなるまい。
I am going to have you open up
to number five, the Gate of Closing,
（ガイ）八門遁甲を
第五の杜門まで開いてもらう。
of the Eight Inner Gates.
八門遁甲…。
術者の体を蝕む禁術ですか？
The Eight Inner Gates.
Is that the Forbidden Jutsu that
eats away at the body of the user?
I am prepared for this.
覚悟はできています！
その禁術を教えてください！
Please teach me the Forbidden Jutsu!
This is all for my dream!
すべては　夢のために！
♪～
あいや～！　とぉ～　とぉ～！
とりゃ～！
♪～
（テンテン）ちょ…　せ　先生！
Sensei!
（ガイ）ハハハハハ…。
ルールだからな。
Those are the rules!
もし俺が負けたら　テンテンを乗せて→
It was decided that if I lose,
I would walk around the village
逆立ちして　里を５００周するって
決めていたんだ。
on my hands 500 times
with you on top.
もう！　勝手に変なルール作って
人を巻き込まないでよ。
Oh boy. Please don't get me
involved with your silly made-up rules.
（ガイ）おう。　ちなみに
もし　テンテンが勝てなかったら→
By the way, if you didn't win,
my punishment for failing
to train you properly
指導が至らなかった罰として
ネジを乗せて→
was to hoist Neji up on top
and do 800 laps!
８００周するつもりだったんだがな。
ハッハッハッ！
It's amazing!
でも　すごいです！
Even if you had a handicap,
you made Guy Sensei lose!
ハンデがあったとはいえ
ガイ先生を負かすなんて！
あ…　私は
私のできることをやっただけよ。
I just did what I could.
ハハハハハ！
テンテンは　忍具のスペシャリストだな。
Tenten, you are a Ninja Tool specialist.
えぇ！　あんな戦い方
テンテンにしかできませんよ！
I'll say! Only Tenten
can battle like that.
忍具の…　アハハ！
Ninja Tools?
（テンテン）私は　忍具のスペシャリストだ！
I'm a Ninja Tool specialist!
《テンテン：何が　忍具のスペシャリストよ…》
Me… A Ninja Tool specialist?
Yeah right.
（ガイ）次こそは　次こそは→
Next, please examine
my student Lee!
我が弟子　リーを
見てやってください！
こっちです！　綱手様！
This way, Lady Tsunade!
＜テンテン：その日　私は→
On that day,
小さかった頃から
憧れ続けた人を初めて見て…。
I saw the person I had admired
ever since I was little for the first time.
そして　その人は…＞
And that person…
（綱手）もう忍は　やめろ。
Forget about being a shinobi.
＜テンテン：リーにとっては→
Her words to Lee were like
a death sentence to him.
死ねと言われるに
等しい言葉を宣告した＞
違う…　違う　違う　断じて違う！
No. No, no, absolutely not!
こんなことがあって
いいはずがない！
Something like this cannot happen!
やっぱり…。
Then does this mean that
determination means nothing?
努力なんて　無駄なのかな…。
やっぱり　才能がないと…。
（ガイ）テンテン。
Does it mean that if
you don't have talent…
Tenten!
リーの覚悟をナメるな。
Don't take Lee's resolve lightly.
お前のこれからと
これまでしてきた→
Nor your own resolve and passion
up to now, and beyond.
努力と熱血をナメるな。
((綱手：手術が成功する確率は
たぶん　よくて５０％。
The odds that the surgery will
be successful are 50% at best.
(失敗すれば…　死ぬ…))
If it fails, you will die.
＜テンテン：だけど　リー
あんたは　その手術を受けた。
But Lee, you underwent the surgery.
そしてすぐ
仲間を助けに行って…＞
And immediately afterwards,
you went to save our friend.
ガイ先生！　テンテン！
Guy Sensei! Tenten!
リー！　リーよ！
Lee! Lee, my boy!
復活したな！
復活したんだな　リー！　リーよ！
You've recovered!
You've bounced right back! Lee!
はい！　ガイ先生
ありがとうございます！
Yes! Guy Sensei,
thank you so much!
（リー）ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
リー！
Lee!
もう！
You!
リー！
Lee!
《テンテン：どんなときでも
あんたは　あきらめなかった。
You never give up,
no matter what!
あんたが頑張るから…
あんたに負けるもんかって→
And because you always go for it,
I tell myself no
だから　私も頑張れたんだ。
負けないでよ…　リー。
こんなことで　負けないで！
リー…　リー！》
《リー！》
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
限界ギリギリでした。
じゃあ　上手くいったの？
（リー）いえ　今までと同じです。
八門遁甲　もう一段上げるには→
もっと激しい特訓が
必要でしょう。
ガイ先生の指導を仰ぎたい
ところですが→
今は　そうもいきませんし。
私でよければ　いくらでも…
つきあうけど…　何してるの？
あっ　おかまいなく
自分ルールですから。
特訓に失敗したら　腕立て伏せ
１万回と決めていたんです。
いつまでかかるのよ…。
１７　１８　１９　どうぞ　おかまいなく。
２３　２４　２５　２６　２７　２８　２９　３０　３１
３２　３３！　うわぁ～っ！
テ　テ　テンテン…　重い…　重いです！
ちょっと～！　その言い方だと
私が重たいみたいじゃない！
「テンテンの出した　金属の人形が重い
重いです」と言いなさい！
ほんと　失礼なんだから！
《私はもう　綱手様のように
なりたいなんて思わない。
でも…　伝説のくノ一になる夢は
まだ　あきらめてはいない》
（美空）　皆様
お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では　最後まで
ごゆっくり　お楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。